Inventory of the Jerdone Family Papers 1753-1890, 1771-1845
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1753-1890. (Box 1-10)
  - Letters, 1810-1819., 148 items. (Box 5-6)
    - Letters, 1812., 15 items. (Box-folder 5:5)
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 June 1812., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Sends port wine and cask of London bottl[e]d "porter"; refers to declaration of war on Britain and her dependencies on the 18th; will send interest as soon as possible.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 2 July 1812., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Sends payment for interest and balance; reports Braikenridge no longer makes kind he [Francis Jerdone] wanted.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 8 August 1812., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Gives update on his sons and their accomplishments; fears correspondence will be difficult with declaration of war; discusses weather and crops.
      - William Browne, W[illia]msb[ur]g, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 September 1812., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Discusses lawsuits of Jerdone's against estate of Wm. Holt; advises best way to be successful; questions desires [of Francis Jerdone] in case.
      - George Divers, Farmington, [?] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 8 November 1812., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Request for loan of eight to ten thousand dollars; encloses bond to be completed by brother Tom in Jerdone's presence.
      - W[illia]m Douglass, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa [County, Virginia], 9 December 1812., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Reports low number of hogs; reports has sold wheat and corn; reports on present corn crop.
    - W[illia]m Douglass, [New Kent County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 31 January 1813., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses conditions of sale of corn.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 13 May 1813., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to order for kegs of Madeira and rum; reports the "seaman's bill" passed the Congress and British were so happy with it they delayed the sailing of troops to the U.S.; reports U.S. troops have taken York in Canada; relays no demand for wheat.
    - William Douglass, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 August 1813., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to illness among slaves; discusses crops and market for corn.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 27 August 1813., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses accounts; refers to weather; relates good news from Spain, but has heard nothing in Germany.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 5 October 1813., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses transportation of articles ordered by Jerdone; refers to the illness of Mr. Pottie and James Govan; feels thinness in "ranks of aquaintances"; reports from Spain contradictory but favorable.
    - W[illia]m Douglass, [Providence Forge, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 December 1813., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses hogs and how they will be split up; discusses harvest and sale of corn and wheat and payment of taxes and wages.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 30 December 1813., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses order for corduroy, mustard, and pepper; reports situation with "hire of labourers"; doesn't feel Jerdone's slaves would average more than $50 for hire because of the war.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 14 June 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports sending of goods; reports abdication of throne by Bonaparte and restoration of Lewis the 18th [Louis XVIII]; refers to hopeful news that commissioners of [U.S.] will settle problems with G[reat] Britain.
      Includes list of goods purchased for him [Francis Jerdone].
    - W[illia]m Douglass, [Providence Forge, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 6 August 1814., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses the illness and death among the slaves from typhus fever; discusses crops and hogs; waiting for visit from the British.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 17 August 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Discusses goods he sent Jerdone; prospects for peace are gloomy; fears war will continue two or three years; afraid to send balance due him by Abram.
      Including account, n.d. 1 page.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 8 October 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports difficulty in getting specie; refers to delivery of cotton; hopes for speedy end to war; refers to rumor of armistice.
      Including list of goods sent, n.d. 1 page.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 December 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to family and weather; reports developments in Europe; refers to negotiations in Ghent; reports on available rum.
    - W[illia]m Douglass, [Providence Forge, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 27 December 1814., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports on accounts; refers to the lying of Davis and his behavior in visiting and drinking with a mulatto; discusses hogs; refers to Jerdone's need of an overseer.
    - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 22 March 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Gives update of family; hopes to hear from Americans soon.
    - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 28 March 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to peace with U.S.; gives update on family; sends message to Dr. Honyman; reports Bonaparte has regained rule in France.
    - Geo[rge] Bralkenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 23 May 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to previous letters; gives account for magazines and conditions for shipment.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 June 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports receipt of letter and tob[acc]o which he will inspect and sell; claims this is a good time to sell it; refers to "no news of importance from Europe."
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 2 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports on the two h[ogs] h[ea]ds of tob[acc]o.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa County, [Virginia], 15 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Refers to enclosed letter from Mr. Bralkenridge; hopes peace has been achieved in Europe; reports on weather and crops.
    - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 27 September 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:6)
      Reports arrival of ship; has forwarded letter from Mr. Braikenridge; refers to magazines.
    - Letters, 1816., 23 items. (Box-folder 5:7)
      - William Mitchell, Jr., Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 January 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Describes articles sent to Jerdone including plough, nails, shoe thread, and others.
      - William Mitchell, Jr. Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 January 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Discusses conditions of sale of tobacco; reports has bought two p[iece]s of linen.
      - William Mitchell, Jr., Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 January 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Describes goods sent; discusses conditions on sale of tobacco; reports cannot give accounts on tobacco yet as it hasn't been weighed.
      - Jno. Lewis, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 January 1816., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports inability to accommodate his [Francis Jerdone] Sons for this year because house is incomplete; describes educational system at his school based on what parent wants taught; discusses tuition and board rates.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his father Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports all three sons are well; describes subjects taken, lists books bought for classes; gives number of students at school; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 25 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports indictment of George Boxley for hiring out Isaack, a Jerdone slave and another man's slave; encloses poem written by Boxley; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 10 June 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports that [brother] W[illia]m is very ill with "running sores," fever and headache; wishes he could be brought home; refers to mother's trip to Hanover.
      - Geo[rge] Harris, Louisa [County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 15 June 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to enclosed copy of proceedings of case involving slaves; has enclosed affidavit for suit against Peter Clarkson; discusses this suit in reference to payment.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 22 June 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports sending of money to pay interest on bonds; refers to no statement because Francis Jerdone hasn't ordered any goods.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 August 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Discusses latest order; fears war will go on two or three years; refers to accounts of last two transactions; refers to the predatory warfare...by the British...on the Potomack [sic]."
      - Geo[rge] Harris, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 August 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Describes conditions and needed persons for taking Mrs. Jerdone's deposition in suit against Clarkson.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 29 August 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Discusses paralytic stroke of "the old Governor"; refers to illness of Mrs. Daniel; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 September 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports "the old Governour" not in good health; refers to violation of [school] rules by many boys including George Mitchell; refers to wheat harvest and lack of butter.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 15 September 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports damage from heavy rains; refers to cases of whooping cough nearby; reports exams beginning; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 5 October 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to crops of Mrs. Lewis and her sale of wheat in Fredericksburg; reports Capt[ai]n Holladay still has his store.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 6 October 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to health; expresses sorrow of Aunt [Mary Jerdone] Toler's illness; relates new regulations on saying lessons; other family news.
      - W[illia]m Douglass, "Providence Forge," [New Kent County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa [County, Virginia], 6 October 1816., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Discusses corn crop and selling prices; reports on hog development; refers to attempt at selling Ho it's land but no bidders.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 October 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to health and weather; relates trip of Mr. Lewis and John Boyer to Fredericksburg; refers to many boys being sent home for winter clothes.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 27 October 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to health of family; sorry to hear of cousin Gardland's wife's illness; refers to speaking to Mr. Lewis about potatoes.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 3 November 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports continued sowing of wheat by Lewis'; refers to better Irish potato crop; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 November 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Refers to birth of daughter to Mr. and Mrs. Lewis; relates dates of vacation; hogs have not yet arrived.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 December 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports Mr. Lewis buying corn and hogs and prices; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his grandmother, Sarah [Macon] Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 6 December 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Reports weather and health; refers to vacation drawing near; other family news.
    - Letters, 1817., 34 items. (Box-folder 6:1)
      - W[illia]m Douglass, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 2 January 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports on crops and hogs; expresses disappointed that there will not be enough cotton to clothe the "people" [slaves] and satisfy other needs; other business news.
      - William Mitchell, Jr., Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 14 January 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Describes articles sent including hat and saddle bags; regrets there is no "English cheese" and not able to get any "London porter."
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 22 February 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Gives schedule of his school day; believes rules are not as bad as he first believed; discusses tuition overseer [description and wages]; and gives other news about school.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 28 February 1817., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Refers to communications; refers to weather and crops; relates economic conditions, employment and prosperity; gives update on sons; relates insurrection in London of lower class; ponders changes that may have taken place since he left Virginia.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 2 March 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Refers to seeing waggoners carrying wheat to Fredericksburg; intends on coming home on Friday as there is no school after 12 o'clock; other family news.
      - T. H. Macon, Mount Prospect, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 5 March 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Approaches prospect of buying the Providence Forge estate.
      - William Mitchell, Jr., Richmond, [Virginia] to his uncle, [Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia], 20 March 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports on goods sent; accepts request to find horses, although thinks it difficult at this time of the year; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 23 March 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports arrival before dinner; refers to health at school.
      - Helen M[acaulay] Anderson, Williamsburg, [Virginia] to her grandmother, Sarah [Macon] Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa County, [Virginia], 28 March 1817., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Laments distance from her relatives; gives report on her children and their schooling; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 30 March 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Gives description of company visiting school; discusses crops of potatoes, peas, and wheat; other local news.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 9 April 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Refers to good health of all; reports Mr. Lewis got home about 10 o'clock on Tuesday.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 19 April 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports on efforts to find a horse; refers to threat of fire to house; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 20 April 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports being sent to stay with Mrs. Lewis; refers to visit by John Boyer; other family news.
      - W[illia]m Douglass, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa [County, Virginia]. 4 May 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Discusses sale of corn; relates bad quality of wheat; would like if Jerdone visited during the summer.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 May 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Refers to Mr. Lewis' trip to Fredericksburg; reports date of vacation; discusses Mr. Lewis' horse.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his Father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 14 May 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports receipt of "Huttons Mathematicks [sic]"; understands these sold for $8 in Fredericksburg; expects to be home in a week.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 30 May 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
        Reports receipt of cherries and Mrs. Lewis' trip to Fredericksburg; sorry to hear of poor Meeny's end; "... did not apprehend that he was going mad."
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 31 May 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports weather and crops; refers to Mrs. Lewis' travels about Virginia; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, ["Llangollen," Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 June 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports rain previous night; discusses Mr. Lewis' potatoes.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 5 June 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Refers to "sty" on his left eye; thanks for the cherries; intends to arrive the following morning; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 14 June 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Refers to "chinches" [bedbugs] and their troublesomeness; reports on crops and their development at the plantation; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 21 June 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Discusses weather and crops; mentions the [Bowdens?] and Faulcon families and visit by Mr. Faulcon.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 5 August 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Complains of "chinches" and condition of room; reports arrivals of boys remarking on absence of Moncures, Travers Daniel and G. Mitchell; discusses Mr. Lewis' crops.
      - W[illia]m Douglass, "Providence Forge," [New Kent County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 8 August 1817., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Discusses sale of wheat and corn; refers to disease among hogs which has decreased number for fattening; reports releasing overseer because of woman he's taken up with; other business and family news; advice on paying the next overseer.
      - John Jerdone, "Llangollen," Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 8 August 1817., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports on crops; refers to various family friends' visits; comments on laziness of the overseer and pay; other family news.
      - John [Jer]done, ["Llangollen," Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 August 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Relates the swelling of the [North Anna] river and problems caused by it; wagon of "Negroe buyers" and 40 slaves stuck, sheep loose.
      - John Jerdone, [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 September 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports on rain and its effects; refers to flooding of schoolhouse; reports on family friends; other family news.
      - John Jerdone, ["Llangollen"], Spotsylvania [County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 4 October 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports he and [brother] Frank have made geographic table of U.S.; gives information on Mrs. Lewis, Doctor Minor and absence of W[illia]m, George [Mitchell] and [?] Crutchfield; refers to weather; reports appointed of classes with nine students in each; refers to tickets [report cards?] and exam on rules.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 15 October 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Gives update on family; refers to health; reports on weather and crops; describes economic situation; refers to lack of Fruit.
      - Francis Jerdone, [Spotsylvania County, Virginia?] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Richmond, [Virginia], 23 October 1817., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports on apple harvest, sowing wheat and corn; gives an update of people at "Llangollen"; reports on visits from Isabella Pottie, Sally Toler, Garland Thompson, and Mrs. Lumbdon.
      - John Jerdone, [Spotsylvania County, Virginia] to his father, Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 9 November 1817., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
        Reports order for Irish potatoes by Mr. Lewis; refers to Frank Harris' visit and his business with Wm. Boyer's suit.